Finding Aid for the Henry Lee Swint Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Series IV: Student Work
  - Student Seminar Papers (arranged topically; number of papers on topic provided in parentheses if more than one)
    - Foreign policy (Box 12)
    - Frank, Leo (Box 12)
    - Fraternalism (Box 12)
    - Freedom (5) (Box 12)
    - Frontier thesis (Box 12)
    - George, Henry (Box 12)
    - Godkin, Lawrence (Box 12)
    - Grady, Henry (Box 12)
    - Harlan County, Kentucky (Box 12)
    - Harrison, Pat (Box 12)
    - Hewitt, Abram Stevens (Box 12)
    - Highlander Folk School (Box 12)
    - Historic Documents (Box 12)
    - Holmes, Oliver Wendell (Box 12)
    - Hubbard, Elbert (2) (Box 12)
    - Immigration (Box 12)
    - Imperialism (4) (Box 12)
    - Individualism (Box 13)
    - Ingersoll, Robert Green (Box 13)
    - Jews (Box 13)
    - Killebrew, Joseph Buckner (2) (Box 13)
    - Literature (3) (Box 13)
    - McClure’s Magazine (Box 13)
    - Mencken, H.L. (Box 13)
    - Military tactics (Box 13)
    - Mims, Edwin (Box 13)
    - Missions (Box 13)
    - Monroe, James (Box 13)
    - Moody, Dwight L. (Box 14)
    - Music (American) (Box 14)
    - Nashville (Box 14)
    - Negroes (6) (Box 14)
    - New York State (Box 14)
    - Patten, Simon Nelsen (Box 14)
    - Philippines (Box 14)
    - Polk, James K. (Box 14)
    - Prohibition (Box 14)
    - Racism (2) (Box 14)
    - Reform (2) (Box 14)
    - Religion (17) (Box 14)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Box 14)
    - Roosevelt, Theodore R. (Box 14)
    - Russell, Richard B. (Box 14)
    - Sanford, Shelton (Box 14)
    - Sanger, Margaret (Box 14)
    - Shelby, Isaac (Box 14)
    - Sherman Act (Box 14)
    - Simms, William Gilmore (Box 14)
    - Sinclair, Upton (Box 14)
    - Slavery (Box 14)
    - Social Christianity (Box 14)
    - Social thought (Box 14)
    - South (4) (Box 14)
    - Steffens, Lincoln (Box 14)
    - Strong, Josiah (Box 14)
    - Sullivan County, Tennessee (Box 14)
    - Tennessee (Box 14)
      Board of Health
      Penal reform
      Temperance
    - Tennessee Valley Authority (Box 14)
    - Traveller’s Rest (Box 14)
    - Willard, Frances (Box 14)
    - Woods, Robert Archey (Box 14)
    - Youmans, Edward L. (Box 14)
    - Unidentified fragment (Box 14)
- Series V: History Department
  - Binkley, William C. -- Correspondence regarding:, 1970-71
  - Comprehensive exam
  - Course outlines
  - Courses
    - History 113 (Box 15)
    - History 171 (5f) (Box 15)
    - History 200 (18f) (Box 15)
    - History 221 (3f) (Box 15)
    - History 285 (17f) (Box 15)
    - History 300 (22f) (Box 16)
    - History 325 (Box 16)
    - History 369 (Box 16)
    - History 370 (Box 16)
    - History 384 (Box 16)
    - History 385 (5f) (Box 16)
    - History 402 (Box 16)
    - History 423 (Box 16)
    - History 429 (Box 16)
    - History 430 (Box 16)
    - History 450 (Box 16)
    - History 534 (Peabody) (Box 16)
    - Recent U.S. (no number) (Box 16)
    - South (no number) (Box 16)
    - History -- unidentified, exams (Box 16)
    - S.S. 101 (10f) (Box 16)
    - Pre-meteorological, history section (ROTC) (Box 16)
  - Curriculum Committee (2f) (Box 17)
  - Departmental seminars (Box 17)
  - Dissertations (Box 17)
  - Fellowships (2f) (Box 17)
  - Gilbert & Sullivan “Ph.D." (musical spoof) (Box 17)
  - Graduate program (3f) (Box 17)
  - Graduate students, c. 1957-67 (2f) (Box 17)
  - Graduates (Box 17)
  - Honors, 1961 and nd (Box 17)
  - Majors, 1960-61 (Box 17)
  - Miscellaneous (3f) (Box 17)
  - Newsletters, 1958, 1963, 1965, 1967-68 (Box 17)
  - Organization of American Historians (Box 17)
  - Periodicals in JUL (Box 17)
  - Ph.D.’s awarded, 1899-1963 (Box 17)
  - Regulations (4f) (Box 17)
  - Searches (2f) (Box 17)
  - Slides (catalog) (Box 17)
  - Woodrow Wilson Fellowships (Box 17)
  - Work Study Program (Box 17)
- Series VI: University Committees and Other Administrative Files
  - “Educational Policy in the College of Arts and Sciences at Vanderbilt University,” by W.B. (Box 17)
  - Jewell, nd (Box 17)
  - Centennial Celebration, 1975 (Box 17)
  - Free University of Nashville, 1969 (Box 17)
  - General information, VU (Box 17)
  - Graduate faculty, 1968 (Box 17)
  - Graduate program regulations (2f) (Box 17)
  - Lawson Case, 1960 (Box 17)
  - Philosophy 234 Survey, nd (Box 17)
  - Committees (Box 17)
    - Applied Mathematics (Box 17)
    - Faculty Council (Box 17)
    - Fallout Shelter (Box 17)
    - Honors Program (Box 17)
    - Humanities (Box 17)
    - Officer Education (Box 17)
    - Oriental Studies (Box 17)
    - Ph.D. Exam (Box 17)
    - Philosophy Ph.D. (Box 17)
    - Publications Board (2f) (Box 17)
    - Race Relations (Box 17)
    - Social Science (Box 17)
    - Student Life (Box 17)
    - Tenure (Box 17)
- Series VII: Institutes on Communism and American Democracy, 1962-1964
  - Correspondence, 1962-63 (Box 18)
  - Expenses and itineraries, 1963-64 (Box 18)
  - News Release, 1963 (Box 18)
  - Participant list, nd (Box 18)
  - Proposal to Vanderbilt University faculty, 1963 (Box 18)
  - Speeches, nd (Box 18)
  - Nature of American Democracy (Box 18)
  - Course outline, including notes and proposals (Box 18)
  - Exams and papers (Box 18)
  - Library reserve list, 1963 (Box 18)
  - Reports and evaluations, 1963 (Box 18)
  - Nature of Communism -- Schedules, booklists, and evaluations, 1962-64 (Box 18)
- Series VIII: Tapes
  - Swint Lectures -- American Social/Intellectual History
    - Tape 1, Side 1 -- The Reformation’s Impact on America (Box 19)
    - Tape 1, Side 2 -- The Sociology of Religion (Box 19)
      The Philosophic Aspects of Puritanism
      The Enlightenment
    - Tape 2, Side 1 -- The Enlightenment (Box 19)
      The Lockean Theory of Government
    - Tape 2, Side 2 -- The Rise of 19th Century Liberalism (Box 19)
      Romanticism and American Transcendentalism
    - Tape 3, Side 1 -- Nationalism (Box 19)
      Transcendentalism
    - Tape 3, Side 2 -- Revivalism and Social Reform (Box 19)
      Emerson, Thoreau and Finney
    - Tape 4, Side 1 -- Reform and Transcendentalism (Box 19)
      Emergence of Abolitionism
    - Tape 4, Side 2 -- Antislavery Controversy (Box 19)
      The Competing Aspects of Antislavery
    - Tape 5, Side 1 -- Continuing Threads: The Legacy of Civil War (Box 19)
      Post-Civil War Industrialism
    - Tape 5, Side 2 -- Sociological Determinism (Box 19)
      Relativism
      Spencer and Sumner
    - Tape 6, Side 1 -- Sociological Determinism (Box 19)
      Darwinism
    - Tape 6, Side 2 -- Sociological Meliorism I (Box 19)
      Sociological and Psychological Determinism and Meliorist Response II
    - Tape 7, Side 1 -- Politics and Sociology (Box 19)
      The Meliorists
      Meliorism and Party Platforms
    - Tape 7, Side 2 -- Religious Reform (Box 19)
      Religious Reform II
      Religious Reform III
    - Tape 8, Side 1 -- Introduction to Pragmatism (Box 19)
      Modernism and Pragmatism
      James and Peirce
    - Tape 8, Side 2 -- Dewey and Instrumentalism (Box 19)
      Dewey and the Revolution of the Educative
      Process
    - Tape 9, Side 1 -- Ideological Origins of Race (Box 19)
      Race v. Racism I
    - Tape 9, Side 2 -- Race v. Racism II (Box 19)
    - Contemporary Arguments (Box 19)
    - The American Characteristic of Mission (Box 19)
  - Swint lectures -- History of Race Relations, 5 tapes, July 1969
  - Other lectures
    - Alexander, William (Professor of Education at University of Miami), 2 tapes: (Box 20)
    - “How Can We Make Teaching More Attractive?,”, June 27, 1957
    - “What Kind of Teachers Do We Want to Get and Keep?,”, June 29, 1957
  - Branscomb, Harvie, “Love and Knowledge,”, June 10, 1956
  - Briarley, H.C., July 27 ?
  - Campbell, Dr. Doak S., August 15, 1958
  - Fleming, Dr. D.F., June 17, 1957
  - Gore, Honorable Albert, Junior Senator from Tennessee, July 5, 1960
  - Herberg, Will
    - “Define Existentialism,”, July 9, 1962 (Box 20)
    - No title, July 10, 1962 (Box 20)
    - Hill, Dr., July 16, 1958 (Box 20)
    - Jones, Howard Mumford, July 16, 1958 (Box 20)
    - Lelyweld, Rabbi Arthur J., July 16, ? (Box 20)
    - Mead, Dr. Margaret, “Emerging American Character,”, July 1, 1957 (Box 20)
    - Miller, Dr. Samuel H., nd (Box 20)
    - Ramsey, Dr., “Woodrow Wilson,”, July 30, ? (Box 20)
    - Rideout, Dr. Walter B. (Professor of English, Northwestern University), “Literature and Politics in Twentieth Century America,”, July 15, 1957 (Box 20)
    - Russell, Anna, in Africa (? -- this could be music) (Box 20)
    - Smart, Dr. Wyatt A., July 24, ? (Box 20)
    - Strickland, Dr. Ruth, “The Pros and Cons of Phonics,”, July 15, 1958 (Box 20)
    - Van Sickle, Dr. Joseph L., August 6, 1956 (Box 20)
  - Vespers
    - Courtenay, Dr. Walter, June 19, 1960 (Box 20)
    - Sittler, Joseph, August 1, ? (Box 20)
    - Smart, Dr., July 15, 1956 (Box 20)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Alumni Club, Denton, Texas, February 12, ? (Box 20)
    - Public Relations Seminars -- Windrow, Dr. J.E. (Box 20)
      - August 13, 1954
      - Summer 1956
      - August 5, 1958 (2 tapes)
    - Swint, Ann -- speeches (2 tapes) (Box 20)
    - Vanderbilt music -- Peabody Chorus (Box 20)
  - Music (Box 21)
  - Russian Language (Box 21)
  - (35 tapes) (Box 21)
  - Unidentified (35 tapes)
- Series IX: Elizabeth Swint Papers
  - Correspondence
    - Dr. Kaser, 1966-69 (Box 22)
    - General, 1962-76 (Box 22)
  - Circulation Services Discussion Group, ALA, 1965-70 (4f)
  - ALA, 1964
  - Central Subcommittee, 1977-78
  - Access control, 1976-78
  - Joint University Libraries Study Committee, c., 1973-75